PERSONAL INFORMATION



Kennedy Kiprotich Kilel

Postal Adress: P.O Box 418-20106, Molo

Cell Phone: 0729712294 Email: kilelken@gmail.com

Sex: Male | Date of birth: 24/04/1986 | Nationality: Kenyan

JOB APPLIED FOR POSITION

TECHNICAL COMMITTEE-KEBS/TC 106 - Dosimetry, radiometry and non-destructive metrology

PERSONAL STATEMENT

To be a renowned nuclear scientist/researcher in an organization of repute where my technical and research skills will be utilized. My goal is to work with a team of scientists in the field of nuclear science and technology to contribute extensively to the research where my conceptual, communication, analytical and problem-solving skills can be effectively utilized. My passion is also in dissemination of knowledge and giving relevant training in my field of expertise

WORK EXPERIENCE

April 2019 - Date

PhD Student/ Researcher on Radiotracer Application

Institute of Nuclear Science and Technology, University of Nairobi

April 2015 - Date

Senior Laboratory Technologist

Kenyatta University

- Coordinating laboratory practical
- Managing of the laboratory: procurement and supervision
- Administration of the laboratory practical
- Supervising post graduate students in the laboratory
- Guiding the post graduate students and undergraduate on the use of the equipment and use of the laboratory facilities

Business or Sector: Academic/Research

August 2012 – March 2019

Senior Laboratory Analyst

Crop Nutrition Laboratory Services

- Method development and validation
- Running of analytical instruments: ICP-OES, Aquakem, FTIR
- Administration of the laboratory practical

EDUCATION ANDTRAINING

April 2019-(Ongoing)

PhD

University of Nairobi

PhD (Nuclear Science)

Title: "Application of Natural Radioactivity as Radiotracer for Sediment

Transport Studies"

November 2011- February

Master of Science(Nuclear science)

2016 University of Nairobi

Nuclear Science

2016-2010 Upper Second Class Honours

Kenyatta University

Bachelor of Science (Analytical Chemistry)

2000-2004 B+

Nakuru West Secondary Scholol

• K.C.S.E

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Kalenjin

Other.	language	(S)	
--------	----------	-----	--

UNDERST	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING			
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production			
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1		
Replace with name of language certificate. Enter level if known.						
C1	C1	C1	C1	C1		
Replace with name of language certificate. Enter level if known.						

Swahili

English

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user

Communication skills

- Good communication skills gained during my lectures and during administration of practical
- Good report writing skills when I worked as senior analyst at crop Nutrition where I used to report results
- Presentation during Tracer 8 conference in Vietnam

Organisational / managerial skills

• Leadership (currently responsible for a team of 6 and at Crop Nutrition was responsible for a team of 10 laboratory analysts)

Job-related skills

Skills in radiotracer application as level II expert trained in CEA/INSTN, Saclay France by IAEA

Nuclear Application Techniques gained when I was undertaking masters research

Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communic ation	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient User	Proficient user		

Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user <u>Digital competences - Self-assessment grid</u>

- Ms word, Ms excel, Ms access, power point etc
- Computer programming (Pascal language, C++), Data Structures and Operating system.
- R-statistical software, SPSS, xlstats, Gensat, and SAS software
- RTD modelling

Driving licence

BCE driving license

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Publications

- 1. Kilel, Kk, Mangala MJ, Gatari MJ, Mathu E, Koech NK (2019). Characterizing Sediments for Black Sands as Possible Radiotracer for Sediment Transport Studies, Conference proceedings on Tracers and Tracing methods, Da Nang, Vietnam.
- Mathu EM, Waswa AK, Kariuki PC, Kianji GK, Odhiambo MB, Kiprotich KK. "THE MIDDLE EASTERN COUNTIES IN KENYA: AN AWAKENING GIANT IN MINING AND IDEAL FOR MINING INVESTMENT." In: GEOEACE. NAIROBI; 2015.
- **3.** Kiprotich, K.K (2016). Characterization of Sands for Heavy Minerals, Distribution and Profiling of River Tiva Sands, Kitui County, South-eastern Kenya. *MSc Thesis*

Conferences

- 8th International Conference on Tracers and Tracing Methods, Da Nang in Vietnam (26th to 28th February 2019)
- School of Agriculture Second Biennial conference in Kenyatta University(29th Nov-2nd December 2016)

Seminars

- AYGN-KYGN Integrated workshop on Nuclear Advocacy and Communication(29-30th November 2017)
- AFRA Counterpart workshop organized by NACOSTI(15-17th November 2017)

Curriculum Vitae

- Seminar on Chemical Security and Safety by Civilian Research and Development Foundation(CRDF)-Global(26th -27th July 2016)
- Seminar on Multi-residue Analytical Techniques by ESTEC-SHIMADZU(26th January 2016)
- Short Course on Application of XRF/XRD/TXRF Techniques by Chroma Africa Training Centre-Nairobi(12th -16th October 2015

Honours and awards

- Awarded scholarship to study Master of Science (Nuclear Science) at Institute of Nuclear Science and Technology, University of Nairobi by Ministry of Energy through Kenya Nuclear Electricity Project (currently Nuclear Power Electricity Agency)
- IAEA Fellowship for training course on Applying radiation technologies in Diagnosing Industrial and Environmental Processes in France (25th June -13th July 2018)

Memberships

- Registered Radiation Worker by Radiation Protection Board (Reg No. ORW/157)
- Membership to East Africa Association of Radiation Protection (EARP)
- International Society of Tracers and Radiation Applications (ISTRA)

Courses

IAEA/Nation Institute for Nuclear Science and Technology (INSTN-CEA)-France

Regional Training course on Applying Radiation Technologies in Diagnosing Industrial and Environmental Processes (TN-RAF1008-1705840)

Certifications

Certification by International Society of Tracers and Radiation Application (ISTRA) on the following techniques:

Tracer and Radiation Application operator: Residence time distribution Technique (RTM/RTD)- Qualification level 2

Tracer and Radiation Application operator: Sealed Sources Method- Scan Techniques (SSM/SCT)- Qualification level 2

References

1. Prof. Benson Mochoge

Professor of Science

Department of Agricultural Science and Technology

Kenyatta University

P.O Box 43844-00100, Nairobi

Cell Phone:+254720874195

Email:bensonmochoge@gmail.com

References

2. Dr. Eng. Isaac Kanda

Chief Geochemist and Research Scientist

Geothermal Development Company

P.O Box 17700, Nakuru Cell Phone: +254720936544 Email: isakandah@gmail.com

3. Mr. Michael Mangala

Lecturer

Institute of Nuclear Science and Technology

University of Nairobi

P.O Box 30197-00100, Nairobi

Cell Phone: 0721578191

Email: michael.mangala@uonbi.ac.ke

ANNEXES

- Copy of master's degree certificate and transcript
- Copy of bachelor's degree certificate and transcripts
- K.C.S.E certificate
- CEA-INSTN training course certificate (Saclay, France)
- Certificate of registration as radiation worker by Radiation Protection Board
- Provision certificate-Tracer and Radiation Applications Operator (sealed sources method and Residence Time Distribution method)
- Certificate of attendance-8th international conference on Tracers and Tracing Methods